Eleazar Pestano

Cell: 604-780-2993 Email: eleazar.pestano@hotmail.com

Summary

Graduate of the BCIT Mechanical Engineering program with previous experience in the HVAC consulting field and currently studying and transitioning to software development (experienced in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React). Passionate, organized and detail-oriented individual.

PORTFOLIO: https://eleazarpestano.netlify.app

Certificates

Code with Mosh

SQL, Data Structures & Algorithms

Present

Design Patterns

September 2024 - October 2024

• The Ultimate Design Patterns (Gang of Four Design Patterns): Part 1 (Creational), Part 2 (Structural), Part 3 (Behavioural)

TypeScript September 2024

The Ultimate TypeScript Course

React

August 2024 – September 2024

React 18: Beginners, Intermediate Topics, Web Design Project

Git August 2024

The Ultimate Git Course

JavaScript July 2024

• Ultimate JavaScript: Part 1 (Fundamentals), Part 2 (Advanced Topics)

HTML5 & CSS3 June 2024 – July 2024

 The Ultimate HTML5 & CSS3 Series: Part 1 (Fundamentals), Part 2 (Advanced Concepts), Part 3 (Web Design Project)

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

British Columbia Institute of Technology – Burnaby, BC

May 2019

88% Cumulative GPA

Diploma in Mechanical Engineering Technology, Design Option

British Columbia Institute of Technology - Burnaby, BC

May 2017

Capstone Project (2019) – Design and Development of a Hybrid Drone

 Worked as Programming Lead in a group of two, applying software control with LabVIEW

2nd Year Design Project (2017) – Design, Modeling and Motion Analysis of a 3D Printer

- Chosen as team lead in a group of four for the project
- Simulated motion analysis on a modelled 3D printer with SolidWorks and LabVIEW

Work Experience

The AME Consulting Group Ltd

Vancouver, BC

Mechanical Designer - Tenant Improvement Team

May 2023 - June 2024

- Design HVAC, plumbing and fire suppression systems for tenant improvement projects using AutoCAD 2022 and Revit 2024, adhering to relevant code (ASHRAE, CSA, BCBC, VBBL, NFPA, etc.).
- Conduct preliminary, progress and final site reviews; review mechanical installation, manage construction oversight and coordination with contractors
- Attend and participate in design meetings with client and owner; ensure client and code requirements are met; provide recommendations and alternate mechanical equipment or system as needed.
- Complete formal construction administration during construction phase, including field reports, progress claim reviews, shop drawing reviews, request for information, change orders and letter of assurances.

Project Coordinator - Commissioning Team

September 2021 - May 2023

- Conduct pre-functional and functional checks and witness start-ups for HVAC and plumbing equipment and systems to verify construction is as per design drawings and specifications.
- Participating in commissioning meetings and record minutes, identifying on-site commissioning-related issues, coordinating with contractors as needed and reporting to Commissioning Authority
- Drafting and finalizing Commissioning Reports, Pre-functional and Functional Check Sheets, Meeting Minutes, O&M Manuals, Commissioning Schedules
- Drafting and submitting proposals; formatting proposals using Adobe InDesign
- Administrative tasks, including scheduling meetings, projects set-ups and close-outs, invoicing, preparing expense reports, coordinating travel arrangements, etc.

CANNEPP Product and Sales Ltd

Delta, BC

Engineer-In-Training

November 2019 – September 2021

- Draft 3D models, fabrication drawings and P&ID drawings piping and supports for hydronic and steam boiler systems using SolidWorks 2021;
- Review, revise and compile technical documents, including BC codes, mechanical schematics, P&IDs, technical specifications, data sheets, installation manuals, operation and maintenance manuals, tender and issue-for-construction document packages

Interest & Hobbies

Fitness passionate about weightlifting, calisthenics and nutrition – strength,

mobility and flexibility;

Outdoor Activities enjoy hiking, snowboarding and volleyball

Gaming enjoy playing multiplayer online battle area and role-playing games

References available upon request